{
    "Section": "Collision Avoidance",
    "SectionNumber": "1",
    "Questions": [
        {
            "Index": "01",
            "Question": "Which statement is true with regard to aircraft converging at approximately the same altitude?",
            "Answers": [
                "A jet airliner has the right of way over all other aircraft.",
                "An aircraft towing objects has the right of way over all power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft.",
                "An aeroplane has the right of way over all other aircraft which are converging from the left.",
                "Aeroplanes towing gliders must give way to helicopters."
            ],
            "Correct": 2,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "02",
            "Question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude",
            "Answers": [
                "both aircraft shall alter heading to the left.",
                "the aircraft on the right shall avoid the other by descending.",
                "the aircraft that has the other on its right shall give way.",
                "the aircraft that has the other on its left shall give way."
            ],
            "Correct": 3,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "03",
            "Question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude, which statement applies?",
            "Answers": [
                "Gliders shall give way to helicopters.",
                "Aeroplanes shall give way to power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft.",
                "Gliders shall give way to aeroplanes.",
                "Power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft shall give way to gliders."
            ],
            "Correct": 4,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "04",
            "Question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude, which statement applies?",
            "Answers": [
                "Gliders shall give way to helicopters.",
                "Aeroplanes shall give way to helicopters.",
                "Helicopters shall give way to aeroplanes.",
                "Helicopters shall give way to gliders."
            ],
            "Correct": 4,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "05",
            "Question": "When two aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude, which statement applies?",
            "Answers": [
                "Gliders shall give way to helicopters.",
                "Aeroplanes shall give way to helicopters.",
                "Helicopters shall give way to aeroplanes.",
                "Gliders shall give way to balloons."
            ],
            "Correct": 4,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "06",
            "Question": "When converging at approximately the same altitude",
            "Answers": [
                "balloons shall give way to hang gliders.",
                "aeroplanes towing gliders shall give way to balloons.",
                "balloons shall give way to gliders.",
                "balloons shall give way to airships."

            ],
            "Correct": 2,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "07",
            "Question": "When two power-driven heavier-than-air aircraft are converging at approximately the same altitude,",
            "Answers": [
                "the one on the left has the right of way.",
                "both shall alter heading to the left.",
                "the one on the right has the right of way.",
                "the one on the right shall give way by descending."
            ],
            "Correct": 3,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "08",
            "Question": "When two aircraft are approaching head-on or approximately so and there is danger of collision, each pilot shall",
            "Answers": [
                "decrease airspeed.",
                "increase airspeed.",
                "alter heading to the right.",
                "alter heading to the left."
            ],
            "Correct": 3,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "09",
            "Question": "When overtaking an aircraft at your 12 o’clock position, at your altitude, you should",
            "Answers": [
                "climb.",
                "descend.",
                "alter heading to the right.",
                "alter heading to the left."
            ],
            "Correct": 3,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        },
        {
            "Index": "10",
            "Question": "Two aircraft are on approach to land, the aircraft at the higher altitude shall",
            "Answers": [
                "have the right of way.",
                "overtake the lower aircraft on the left.",
                "give way.",
                "complete a 360° turn to the right."
            ],
            "Correct": 3,
            "References": [
                "TC AIM-RAC - Collision Avoidance - Right of Way",
                "CARs 602.19 - Right of Way"
            ]
        }
    ]
}